<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-10-04T16:59:27-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ethical Frenchie</title><subtitle>We are a family and friends based French Bulldog Breeder located in New York, NY. We welcome you to Learn more about us and our Ethically Bred French Bulldog puppies.</subtitle><author><name>James</name><email>james@ashlandharrison.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Most Common Mistakes French Bulldog Owners Make</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/most-common-mistakes-french-bulldog-owners-make" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Most Common Mistakes French Bulldog Owners Make" /><published>2020-08-05T00:35:04-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-05T00:35:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post29</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/most-common-mistakes-french-bulldog-owners-make">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;French Bulldog.&lt;/strong&gt; The funny, loyal, loving, and “issue prone” dog that is loved by so many around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldogs originated from France about 150 years ago, but only really started gaining momentum in the last 5-7 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every pure bred dog comes with its set of issues, due to breeding for certain traits that don’t always promote health. Even though some French Bulldog issues can’t be eliminated, there are still a few approaches that will in our opinion add to the quality of life of your bully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some common mistakes bulldog owners, and dog owners in general make. We challenge you to read books and educate yourself on the topics below, and make a change if the new knowledge steers you into that direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image-of-raw-meat-in-a-bowl.png&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-improper-diet&quot;&gt;1.	Improper Diet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is only one diet that is biologically appropriate for your dog and it’s not kibble nor is it cooked food, even though cooked food is a better alternative to kibble for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the raw diet. Raw meat, raw bones, organs, eggs, veggies. It’s the only diet that will give your dog a great start at life, prevent skeletal disease French bulldogs are “so prone to” (read hip dysplasia, patellar luxation, etc..), and reduce your vet visit frequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The **BARF diet **is very simple and when you learn more about it, a logical approach to feeding your dog. Have you ever seen a wolf hunt down an animal, collect the meat, then bake it on a high temp to turn it into kibble? No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commercial dog food gained momentum in 1950, which conveniently correlates with the &lt;strong&gt;increase of dog cancer, skeletal disease, bladder stones, arthritis, and an increase of allergies in dogs&lt;/strong&gt;. Before that dogs ate raw meat, raw bones, and other table scraps. We forced our dogs to adapt to a diet that they weren’t meant to consume, for our own convenience and its affecting them on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s never too late to reverse some of the damage that was done by feeding your Frenchie improperly. Owners report elimination of allergies, ear infections, arthritis and other modern day dog problems we often hear about - after switching to species appropriate diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image-of-a-needle.png&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-over-vaccination&quot;&gt;2.	Over-Vaccination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_What vaccines does my French Bulldog need? _&lt;strong&gt;The answer is less is more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend giving your puppy the core DHPP vaccine at 12 weeks and another booster at 16 weeks. That vaccine will protect your dog for at least 5-6 years, or in some cases lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are unsure about the level of immunity your dog has towards infectious diseases you can request a blood titer. Your veterinarian will draw blood and check the number of antibodies still present. If the amount is low then you should consider re-vaccinating, but that is rarely the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Rabies shot?** Of course. Rabies vaccination is required by law. There is also no cure for rabies, so if your dog gets infected there isn’t much you can do. And let’s not forget rabies is zoonotic, meaning it can transfer to humans. Again, a blood titer test can be required to check the level of immunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** 
_What about Bordatella, Lyme, Leptospirosis? 
_**Those are called lifestyle vaccines. They need to be injected yearly and unfortunately often don’t offer 100% protection. If you don’t live in a geographical area that is very prevalent in leptospirosis or tick born disease, then vaccination for those can be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_**Bordatella? **_Bordatella vaccine protects your dog from kennel cough and it’s recommended if your dog lives in a kennel where the cough could potentially spread rapidly between a big number of dogs and puppies. If your dog is a family pet and doesn’t visit boarding facilities too often, then this vaccine should in my opinion be avoided. But the choice is yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/non-core-vaccines-for-dogs/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read More About The Non-Core Vaccines By Clicking Here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are taking great care of your dog, feeding it properly, and avoiding over-vaccination you will be a proud owner of a Frenchie with an extremely healthy immune system, so chances of your dog ACTUALLY catching a virus will be very slim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, every vaccination lowers your dogs immune system to a sometimes irreparable degree, putting it at risk for allergies, cancers, neurological issues, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/whats-in-your-dogs-vaccine/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click here to read more about over-vaccination and what are the ingredients of the vaccines your dog receives&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post is written by a Doctor of Veterinary Medicine that has 20+ years of experience in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image-of-a-cute-frenchie-puppy.png&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-early-spayneuter&quot;&gt;3. Early Spay/Neuter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggesting an early spa is a very standard practice in today’s veterinary medicine, but early spaying/neutering is a very gray area, with some clinics trying to schedule the procedure as soon as possible vs. informing you it’s important to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do understand the problem with pet overpopulation, which is why early spay is highly suggested nowadays. However, there are some downsides to an early spay that owners often aren’t informed about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yourpurebredpuppy.com/health/articles/neutering-male-dog.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pros and Cons of Neutering Your Male Dog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yourpurebredpuppy.com/health/articles/spaying-female-dog.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pros and Cons of Spaying Your Female Dog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_What is the downside of an early spay? _&lt;/strong&gt;There are so many downsides of an early spay that the owners aren’t informed about when committing to the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like every pet owner should be presented with all pros and cons and make a decision based on facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**By spaying/neutering your French Bulldog early you are potentially putting it at risk for **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Life long low immunity (dogs immune system doesn’t fully develop until the age of 2-3. There are certain reproductive hormones needed to achieve that),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skeletal problems that are very common in the breed like hip dysplasia, patellar luxation, IVDD and more..&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bone cancer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obesity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyroid problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/health-risks-of-early-spay-neuter/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read More About Potential Risks By Clicking Here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_So when should you ideally spay/neuter in our opinion?  _&lt;/strong&gt;We suggest waiting until your French Bulldog female is at least 15 months old, and your male is 2 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image-of-a-tick.png&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-tickfleaheartworm-prevention&quot;&gt;4.	Tick/Flea/Heartworm Prevention&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simparica, Bravecto, Nextguard, Heartguard.. I’m sure you are very familiar with the names and chances are your Frenchie is on at least one if not multiple of these preventative treatments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at how these anti-parasitic treatments work. Each of the above-mentioned treatments contains small dosages of neurotoxins that paralyze and eventually kill the parasite. The poison is fed to your dog and builds up in their skin. Once the flea or tick tries to attach to your dog it instantly kills it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these brands claim that the amount of poison released is so small it’s completely safe for your dog. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But is it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was not a single study done about the side effects of giving your dogs small amounts of poison these products contain for several years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We challenge you to do research and join Facebook groups/talk to other pet owners, before giving any of the preventative treatments to your dog. The products were put under the microscope multiple times after owners reported seizures, severe allergic reactions and even death of their beloved pet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t use it for our dogs and would not take the risk due to all the adverse side effects reported over the years, but the decision is yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some products that we personally use on our adult dogs as well as our little puppies. They are organic and for us, they work like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31hcwko&quot;&gt;Wondercide Natural Products - Flea, Tick and Mosquito Control Spray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2PrlZA7&quot;&gt;EcoFlea by ColoradoDog - all Natural Chewable Dog Treats for Flea and Tick Treatment and Prevention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/33BBUUy&quot;&gt;Vet’s Best Flea and Tick Home Spray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_What about Heartworm Prevention Medicine? _&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much to say about heartworm medicine prevention and mostly about how unnecessary it is to give it year round. It all makes complete sense once you learn about the heartworm larvae life cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/dont-give-dogs-heartworm-meds-shouldnt-either/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn why Heartworm prevention shouldn’t be given year round.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/image-of-dogs-playing.png&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-improper-exercise-of-a-young-puppy&quot;&gt;5.	Improper Exercise Of a Young Puppy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young puppy is a puppy that is still growing. Their bones are soft and not fully developed, joints not fully formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common mistake we see owners do is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_Drag their puppy when it’s refusing to walk on the leash. _&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get it, it can be frustrating, but by doing that you are severely damaging those growing bones and setting your dog up for skeletal problems later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have their puppy perform tricks on their hind legs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no reason a growing puppy should be putting extra weight on its back legs until the bones are done growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldogs or any dogs for that matter should only be involved in puppy play and very short walks until their bones are done growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is usually over by the time they reach sexual maturity. There are certain hormones that play a big role in bone growth, so going back to number 3, spaying them early, and removing those essential hormones sets them up for skeletal disease later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-you-make-the-changes&quot;&gt;Will You Make The Changes?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you made it this far congratulations. You will now be able to implement some of our tips and transform your approach when it comes to dog care. The results will be a healthy, happy doggo, fewer vet visits, and longer life expectancy. Now it’s your turn. Will you make the changes?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Harrison</name></author><category term="French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Health," /><category term="Diet," /><category term="Health" /><category term="Problems," /><category term="Care" /><category term="French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Health," /><category term="French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Diet," /><category term="French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Health" /><category term="Problems," /><category term="French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Care" /><summary type="html">French Bulldog. The funny, loyal, loving, and “issue prone” dog that is loved by so many around the globe.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/french-bulldog-mistakes.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/french-bulldog-mistakes.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Prevent IVDD In French Bulldogs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/french-bulldog-ivdd-prevention" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Prevent IVDD In French Bulldogs" /><published>2020-08-04T19:54:23-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-04T19:54:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post28</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/french-bulldog-ivdd-prevention">&lt;p&gt;If you are researching the Frenchie breed or getting a French Bulldog in the near future, one of the first conditions you need to familiarize yourself with is IVDD. IVDD is a serious condition that is French Bulldogs are genetically predisposed to due to being “low rider dogs” aka dogs with short legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog we will talk more about what IVDD is, the symptoms, as well as prevention. IVDD can be  prevented but is often not due to lack of knowledge, so hopefully you will be more informed and able to take preventative measures after finishing this read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-french-bulldog-ivdd&quot;&gt;What is French Bulldog IVDD?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intervertebral disc disease (IVDD) is a condition where the cushioning discs between the vertebrae of the spinal column either bulge or burst (herniate) into the spinal cord space. These discs then press on the nerves running through the spinal cord causing pain, nerve damage, and even paralysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IVDD is a disease that effects the spinal cord over time, but it might not be apparent until there is a trigger. Unfortunately, a dog who appears to be completely healthy one day may take a fall or jump in such a way that a disc becomes ruptured. IVDD is a degenerative (gradual) process, but a jump or fall can damage a disc that has already been weakened by IVDD and bring on an acute phase of the disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/French-bulldog-excercise-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black French Bulldog Puppy with a female veterinarian&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-recognize-the-symptoms-of-ivdd-in-french-bulldogs&quot;&gt;How to recognize the symptoms of IVDD in French Bulldogs?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Made up of a gelatinous substance surrounded by a thick outer layer, intervertebral discs are basically the shock absorbers of the spine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of disc herniation seen in dogs: Type I and Type II, of which Type II generally has less severe signs and symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognizing the symptoms of IVDD in French Bulldogs and offering &lt;strong&gt;instant medical attention&lt;/strong&gt; is the crucial part of the recovery process. If these symptoms appear visit a vet &lt;strong&gt;RIGHT AWAY.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Symptoms can range from mild to severe and can include:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Unwillingness to jump&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Pain and weakness in rear legs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Knuckling under&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Paralysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Crying out in pain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Muscle spasms over back or neck&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Hunched back or neck with tense muscles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Reduced appetite and activity level&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Loss of bladder and/or bowel control&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;diagnosing-and-reversingtreating-ivdd&quot;&gt;Diagnosing and reversing/treating IVDD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A veterinary examination will generally include a neurological exam, X-rays, and/or special imaging (myelogram, CT scan, MRI) to locate the source of spinal injury. If the diagnosis reveals mild to moderate injury, treatment may include the administration of steroids and anti-inflammatory medications to reduce swelling and pain, with confined rest required for four to six weeks or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In more severe cases, surgery may be advised to open up the space around the spinal cord. Surgery has a better chance of being successful if the dog has not lost the ability to walk and if surgery is done very soon after diagnosis (within 24 hours). If a dog has already lost the ability to walk before surgery, the prognosis is not optimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post-surgical physical rehabilitation is often recommended for muscle strengthening. If a surgery is not successful, a dog wheelchair is often recommended, which can give the dog a healthy, active life despite the disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Blue-Frenchie-pup-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White French Bulldog Chewing on a toy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-steps-to-prevent-ivdd-in-french-bulldogs&quot;&gt;7 Steps To Prevent IVDD in French Bulldogs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a future French Bulldog owner, it’s important to get as familiar with the breed as possible. A responsible breeder will inform you about potential risks as well as measures of prevention when it comes to French Bulldog IVDD prevention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IVDD isn’t something all French Bulldogs develop. A genetic predisposition doesn’t equal disease onset. However it is very important to follow these preventative measures to lower the possibility of your Frenchie being affected as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.	Keep Your French Bulldog  PUPPY As Lean as Possible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important step to prevent IVDD in French Bulldogs is to keep your dog’s weight down to eliminate extra stress on the neck and back. Like we mentioned in a previous blog, the ideal body shape is one where the waist can be visible, and ribs easily felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puppyhood weight will determine adulthood weight. If you are over-feeding your French Bulldog puppy, the dog will develop more fat cells, which equals a fat adult. So this right here is a number one mistake owners make right there. They want a cute, chunky, roly-poly pup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately that equals - health problems in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**2.	Harness Vs. Collar 
**Use a harness when walking your French Bulldog. Not only can using a collar cause difficulty breathing in a brachycephalic dog breed, but it can also put extra stress on the neck and put your dog at risk for IVDD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31iR92f&quot;&gt;BARKBAY No Pull Dog Harness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2XuAqrA&quot;&gt;WALKTOFINE Dog Harness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31h6Cjm&quot;&gt;Truelove Soft Front Dog Harness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**3.	Limit Jumping
**This is a hard one, I know. They are dogs and of course they love being active, which involves high impact activities like jumping on and off high furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if a ramp/doggie stairs case is introduced at a young age and your Frenchie is trained to use only that specifically, they might never realize that jumping from beds and couches is even an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IVDD in French Bulldog really is no joke, so don’t hesitate to get a doggie ramp sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2DcNafH&quot;&gt;Click to get yours.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**4.	Healthy Diet
**Feed your French Bulldog a high quality diet consisting of animal protein as it’s first ingredient to promote lean muscle growth. 99% kibbles on the market unfortunately do not contain the adequate amount of meat, or should we say an adequate amount of anything,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your dog needs to be fed a raw diet that consists of raw meaty bones, meat and organs. The bones will build a solid skeleton for your dog, unlike artificial calcium supplements found in kibble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also can’t expect to produce puppies with healthy skeletons if the pregnant bitch is fed a cereal based, calcium supplemented commercial dog food. Puppy growth starts in the womb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/french-bulldog-feeding-the-raw-diet/&quot;&gt;**To learn more about the biologically appropriate diet for dogs, also called BARF, click here. **&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**5.	Do not Spay/Neuter until your dog is fully grown. 
**You can stunt your dogs growth by spaying/neutering early on. Let your French Bulldog grow fully before committing to the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fixing your puppy at an early age not only puts them at risk for IVDD, but also puts them at risk for hip dysplasia, obesity and bone cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Useful reading material below, if you are curious to learn more about the ideal time to spay/neuter your pet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yourpurebredpuppy.com/health/articles/spaying-female-dog.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.Positives and negatives of neutering your male dog
**](https://www.yourpurebredpuppy.com/health/articles/neutering-male-dog.html)[&lt;/strong&gt;2.Positives and negatives of spaying your female dog.
**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this blog provided you with the knowledge needed to prevent IVDD onset in your French Bulldog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, if IVDD symptoms arise seek medical attention right away. Every hour is crucial and waiting too long can cause irreversible damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Renee</name></author><category term="List" /><category term="[" /><category term="&quot;French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Care&quot;," /><category term="Health&quot;," /><category term="Life" /><category term="Expectancy&quot;," /><category term="Lifespan&quot;" /><category term="]" /><category term="List" /><category term="[" /><category term="&quot;French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Care&quot;," /><category term="&quot;French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Health&quot;," /><category term="&quot;French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Life" /><category term="Expectancy&quot;," /><category term="&quot;French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Lifespan&quot;" /><category term="]" /><summary type="html">If you are researching the Frenchie breed or getting a French Bulldog in the near future, one of the first conditions you need to familiarize yourself with is IVDD. IVDD is a serious condition that is French Bulldogs are genetically predisposed to due to being “low rider dogs” aka dogs with short legs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/french-bulldog-ivdd-prevention.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/french-bulldog-ivdd-prevention.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Food For a French Bulldog - Our 2020 Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/best-food-for-french-bulldog" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Food For a French Bulldog - Our 2020 Guide" /><published>2020-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post11</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/best-food-for-french-bulldog">&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-pick-the-best-food-for-a-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;How to pick the Best Food for a French Bulldog?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;follow-our-2020-guideline-below&quot;&gt;Follow our 2020 guideline below!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, kibble is very convenient and that’s what a big portion of dogs owners worldwide feeds, but is it really the best option for your dog? As a responsible dog owner you are probably what is the &lt;strong&gt;best food for a French Bulldog in 2020?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s just start by saying, dogs just like humans, require fresh food to thrive. Your French Bulldog will experience less issues if fed a high quality raw diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you can find some diets as well as food brands we recommend. You will not find any type of kibble on this list, as kibble is not a recommended style of feeding if you want to keep your French Bulldog healthy and issue free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-barf-diet---biologically-appropriate-raw-diet&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The BARF Diet - Biologically Appropriate Raw Diet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/raw-dog-food.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of honest kitchen dog food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best food you can feed your dog, and that applies to all dogs, not just French Bulldogs is a completely raw diet that consists of raw meat, raw bones, raw veggies, raw eggs,.. It’s the diet that your dog is designed to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No your dog is not designed to eat baked kibble or cooked protein. The heat damages the protein which prevents correct absorption by the dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is not a raw feeding guide. This is a blog about recommended dog foods for your French Bulldog, and even though the raw diet should be the first choice, we understand it’s not doable for every pet parent.** **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ziwi-peak-air-dried-raw&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ziwi Peak Air Dried Raw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ziwipeak-dog-food.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Ziwi Peak air dried dog food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow. So &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31mHGH9&quot;&gt;Ziwi Peak &lt;/a&gt;is one of the best air dried raw dog foods I ever came across. If you are a dog food connoisseur, like myself then you will be blown away by their ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meat is organic and free range, they focus on creating a balanced meal by pairing the right foods together and not by relying on supplements and additives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be my second choice, if feeding completely raw is not an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ziwi Peak is carried by Amazon, which is another plus. You can shop their food by clicking &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31mHGH9&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stella-and-chewys-dehydrated-raw-food&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stella and Chewy’s Dehydrated Raw Food&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/stella_chewy_food.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Stella Chewy's Dog Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2EKCIw4&quot;&gt;Stella and Chewy’s &lt;/a&gt;is a very popular brand in the dog world. They are notorious for their dehydrated raw dinner patties as well as other raw food toppers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose between so many different protein types, including rabbit, in case your have a highly allergic and sensitive pup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sojos-freeze-dried-raw-food&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sojos Freeze Dried Raw Food&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/sojos-raw-dog-food.png&quot; alt=&quot;Farmers Dog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3i71GUJ&quot;&gt;**Sojos **&lt;/a&gt;is another freeze dried raw food brand with clean ingredients. Non GMO, no fillers, and super convenient if you travel and don’t want to feed fully raw. Sojos comes in powder form, so all you have to do it re-hydrate it with water, bone broth, goat milk, or a mixture of them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;instinct&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instinct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/raw-instinct-dog-food.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the Instinct Raw dog food packaging&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/33mxT6y&quot;&gt;Instinct&lt;/a&gt; is a brand that offers the &lt;strong&gt;Best food for a French Bulldog&lt;/strong&gt;. You can pick between their frozen  and dehydrated raw options or raw coated kibble. If kibble is your go-to then picking one with some dehydrated raw meat is better than not doing it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I started preparing my own raw food I used Instinct, religiously, and I think it’s the &lt;strong&gt;best dog food for french bulldog with skin allergies.&lt;/strong&gt; The ingredients are very limited and you can easily eliminate the allergen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instinct raw can be found at every PetSmart and Petco in their fridge section, but you can also shop the freeze-dried version &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/33mxT6y&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spot-farms&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spot Farms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/spot-farms-dog-food.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Ollie Dog Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3i75wND&quot;&gt;Spot Farms&lt;/a&gt; is another powered dehydrated raw dog food that is conveniently carried by Amazon and can be delivered to you anywhere at anytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human grade ingredients and full of nutrients as the meat is only lightly processed by dehydrating it. The meat is never cooked or baked so the important nutrients like vitamins, amino acids and fatty acids remain in the food by the end of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can pick between different flavors like chicken, duck, pork, turkey,..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can shop Spot Farms dog food &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3i75wND&quot;&gt;here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-summarize&quot;&gt;To Summarize&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you will be able to pick the &lt;strong&gt;best food for French Bulldog&lt;/strong&gt; puppies and adults, after reading our blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last recommendation would be -**if you are feeding a different kind of food, like fresh food or kibble, make sure to implement some raw food into your dogs diet in some form, even if it’s only by sprinkling some freeze dried raw food toppers on top. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is a list of ingredients you can add to your dogs diet to boost or add the ingredients the diet lacks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2EJefaq&quot;&gt;** Bone Broth**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3gsrb2s&quot;&gt;** Probiotics and Enzymes **&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/39WZE75&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Omega 3 Plankton&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2XpEVU3&quot;&gt;** Hemp Seed Oil**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2DjzcbK&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raw food toppers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raw Green Veggies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALSO if you simply cannot bring yourself to feed any kind of raw food, even the air-dried one, then cook for your dog. Lightly cook the eat and veggies, to prevent the nutrients from being destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="Best 2019 Dog Foods" /><category term="French Bulldog Fresh Food" /><category term="French Bulldog Dog Food" /><category term="Best Food For French Bulldogs" /><category term="List" /><category term="[" /><category term="&quot;Best" /><category term="2020" /><category term="Dog" /><category term="Foods&quot;," /><category term="&quot;French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Fresh" /><category term="Food&quot;," /><category term="&quot;French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Dog" /><category term="Food&quot;," /><category term="&quot;Best" /><category term="Food" /><category term="For" /><category term="French" /><category term="Bulldogs&quot;" /><category term="]" /><summary type="html">How to pick the Best Food for a French Bulldog?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/best-food-for-french-bulldogs.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/best-food-for-french-bulldogs.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Thorough Understanding of Nutrients for French Bulldogs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/a-thorough-understanding-of-nutrients-for-french-bulldogs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Thorough Understanding of Nutrients for French Bulldogs" /><published>2020-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/a-thorough-understanding-of-nutrients-for-french-bulldogs">&lt;p&gt;Frenchies are among the most favorite pets of worldwide households because of their lovable companionship. Therefore, no wonder you want to spare the best food for your furry friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, not all brands of commercial dog food on the market are healthy enough for their digestive system. It depends on which ingredients are mixed. Understanding pet food labels is also an excellent way to take better care of your Frenchie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s sort out the essential &lt;strong&gt;nutrients for French bulldogs&lt;/strong&gt; you should always keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vital-nutrients-for-french-bulldogs&quot;&gt;Vital nutrients for French Bulldogs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/vital-nutrients.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of food containing vital nutrients for french bulldog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;protein&quot;&gt;Protein&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies show that protein can bring about numerous benefits to bodies upon consumption. It supplies protein subunits or amino acids to build nails, skin, tendons, ligaments, muscles, and cartilage. Besides, protein is one of the essential substances for the production of hormones. Protein for Frenchies is rich in fish, poultry, meat, and some plant ingredients, including soybean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How about protein in plants?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soybean meal is known as a by-product created during the production of soybean oil. For that reason, not many labels welcome soy products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meat used in Frenchie food should be the clean flesh of slaughtered lamb, turkey, chicken, or cattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/protein-raw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of raw chicken protein&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, there are striated skeletal muscle, diaphragm, esophagus, tongue, and heart attached in that flesh. Hair, horns, hooves, teeth, and feathers will get completely removed so as not to mix with the fresh meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though high protein dog food is necessary for your French pup, such diets would be detrimental to sick dogs’ health. In this case, make sure to go for low protein dog food to help relieve symptoms and push up the recovery process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/IGCTA2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;carbohydrates&quot;&gt;Carbohydrates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plants and grains are two primary sources that supply carbohydrates for your Frenchies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbohydrates, known to provide bulk and energy, are in two categories, including fibers and starches, or sugars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fibers are products of fermentation that produce short-chain fatty acids thanks to bacteria in dog intestines. Large amounts of such acids can come from highly fermentable fiber sources like vegetable gums. While moderately fermentable fibers (available in beet pulp, etc.) supply both acids and bulk for moving waste via digestive tracts, slightly fermentable fibers mainly provide bulk and only a limited number of fatty acids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comprised starches are of many different types of sugar (including fructose and glucose), which can get easily converted into usable energy through dogs’ digestive mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vitamins-and-minerals&quot;&gt;Vitamins and minerals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the list of the &lt;strong&gt;best nutrients for French bulldogs&lt;/strong&gt;, the enormous benefits of vitamins can be by no means neglected. They enhance blood clotting, bone growth, produce energy, and prevent oxidation. To facilitate the absorption of vitamin C into the body, water is required, whereas, vitamins A, D, E, and K ask for the provision of fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minerals are helpful in muscle contractions and nerve transmissions besides providing support for the development of skeletons. Phosphorous, a vital mineral for senior dogs’ cellular repair and puppies’ growth, can be seen on many dog food labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fat&quot;&gt;Fat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fats are another necessary substance for dogs to take in through eating food. Once digested, they can provide bodies with necessary fat subunits, omega-3, and omega-6 fatty acids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/fat-protein.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of fat rich raw salmon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous studies have indicated that omega-3 fatty acids play a crucial role in decreasing inflammation and blood clotting while omega-6 fatty acids serve to maintain proper membrane structure as well as enhance Frenchie’s coat and skin. Fats are the primary source of stored energy found in the body, which can provide a two-fold amount of energy compared to proteins or carbohydrates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fats are abundant in fish, poultry, meat and plant oils, namely flax and vegetable oils, so such kinds of food are in many vets’ recommendations for dog diets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here to check out the&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/french-bulldog-care-13-best-dog-food-brands/&quot; title=&quot;Best Dog Food for French Bulldogs&quot;&gt; Best Dog Food for French Bulldogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;list-of-ingredients-to-avoid&quot;&gt;List of ingredients to avoid&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the mass influx of dog food brands on the market, Frenchie owners may get confused as to which brand supplies healthy dog food for their little French fellow’s development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some pet food companies even exaggerate their products’ benefits to deceive consumers. Knowing unhealthy dog food ingredient lists can help you avoid choosing the unhealthy food type. Beside the &lt;strong&gt;vital nutrients for French bulldogs&lt;/strong&gt;, what are the ingredients to avoid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bhabht&quot;&gt;BHA/BHT&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are chemical preservatives used to preserve fats in pet foods. Knowing for their link to causing child hyperactivity and cancer. Several countries have banned the use of this illness trigger in food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;white-flour&quot;&gt;White flour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This simple carbohydrate is the leading cause of hunger soon after consumption in dogs due to spikes and drops in blood sugar. Consuming an excessive amount of white flour can increase the risks of dogs getting diagnosed with obesity or diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;farmed-salmon&quot;&gt;Farmed salmon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although salmon is healthy for your canines, the salmon that has not passed quarantine regulations might contain harmful toxins. A typical example is farmed-salmon, mentioned as salmon meals or salmon oil on food packages. It can increase the percentage of mercury and other fat-soluble toxins in your dog’ diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;msg-monosodium-glutamate&quot;&gt;MSG (monosodium glutamate)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepared foods often use MSG to enhance flavor, deceiving dogs’ taste in case low-quality ingredients cannot produce enough tasty flavor. MSG is not only useless in terms of nutrition but also a common allergen to diverse dog breeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than seeing MSG written on labels, MSG is abundant in other ingredients such as hydrolyzed protein, texturized protein, yeast extracts, autolyzed yeast, sodium caseinate, disodium inosinate, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gluten&quot;&gt;Gluten&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to human beings, many Frenchies develop &lt;a href=&quot;https://petlifebuzz.com/dog-allergies-faqs-and-food-recommendations/&quot;&gt;allergies&lt;/a&gt; to gluten-containing grains found in corn, wheat, or oats. Because of an overkill on grains, your companions may suffer from digestive distress, followed by chronic ear infections, hot spots or itching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acknowledging the good and the bad is never a waste. Understanding the harmful factors that take your fluffy companion’s health is worth every minute to spare. Get your furry fellow live a lifelong happily with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preservatives&quot;&gt;Preservatives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like other packaged food, chemicals are there to keep it fresh until use. Several common preservatives are tocopherols, rosemary, ascorbic acid, which are of natural origin to minimize chances of food spoilage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, manufacturers of canned dog food don’t use preservatives because the canning process has left out the need for chemical support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;artificial-colors&quot;&gt;Artificial colors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are worthless processed type colors added to food to make it more visually attractive. They are found to cause biochemical processes within bodies besides hyperactivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chemical-flavors&quot;&gt;Chemical flavors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fake taste and colors may trigger your &lt;a href=&quot;https://frenchbulldog.nyc/about-the-french-bulldog-breed/&quot;&gt;French bulldog&lt;/a&gt; to consume more food, but it leaves off the detrimental waste in the body in the long run. Those chemical uses are indigestible and likely to form stones in organs leading your Frenchies to sickness at their senior time. It is best to avoid such ingredients in any commercial food you buy for your little pup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome-a-healthy-frenchie&quot;&gt;Welcome a healthy Frenchie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, pet owners should conduct comprehensive research on all dog food brands to pick out the best dog food suited for their pets’ health condition. Refer to the list mentioned above of common ingredients as well as harmful ones, or consult a veterinarian if necessary, and you can make informed decisions in the interests of your lovely friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in making your own food? Click here for &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/home-cooked-food-for-your-french-bulldog-ethical-frenchie/&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldog Food Recipes&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Food Recipes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Care" /><category term="Nutrients For French Bulldog" /><category term="Best French Bulldog Foods" /><category term="French Bulldog Health" /><category term="french bulldog theft" /><category term="frenchie theft" /><category term="featured" /><category term="pick" /><summary type="html">Frenchies are among the most favorite pets of worldwide households because of their lovable companionship. Therefore, no wonder you want to spare the best food for your furry friends.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-nutrients.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-nutrients.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Top 5 DIY Summer Treats For Your French Bulldog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/top-5-diy-summer-treats-for-french-bulldog" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top 5 DIY Summer Treats For Your French Bulldog" /><published>2020-08-03T23:42:05-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T23:42:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post30</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/top-5-diy-summer-treats-for-french-bulldog">&lt;p&gt;Summer is here and our French bulldogs are as heat intolerant as ever.  We explored Pinterest in search of easy DIY doggie treats that will keep our furry friends cool and entertained during the hot months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are our top 5 DIY Frozen Treat picks. Fun, easy to make and so delicious looking. I’m honestly tempted to make them…for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy preparing them and encourage you to post the final product on Instagram and tag @EthicalFrenchie. 
We would love to see it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31dg6vG&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super motivated to  recreate these but don’t have the paw shaped ice molds? We got you. Click here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/watermelon-dog-treats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of watermelon dog treats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-watermelon-dog-treats-by-bark-and-biscuits&quot;&gt;1.	Watermelon Dog Treats By Bark and Biscuits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	2 cups seedless watermelon pureed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1/2 cup Plain Greek Yogurt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1 tbsp parsley chopped&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INSTRUCTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Puree seedless watermelon in a blender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop parsley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place mold on baking tray. If you are using the paw molds, first insert a small piece of parsley into the bottom then add a thin layer of plain Greek yogurt. Freeze for one hour. Next, fill the remaining mold with watermelon puree. Freeze overnight or at least 4 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the dog bone mold, add a piece of parsley to the bottom of mold and spoon in a layer of watermelon puree. Freeze one hour. Next, add a layer of plain Greek yogurt. Freeze one hour. Finally, add another layer of watermelon puree and freeze overnight or at least 4 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep frozen until ready to serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mint-dog-treats.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of paw shaped mint dog treats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-frozen-fresh-breath-treats&quot;&gt;2.	Frozen Fresh Breath Treats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	5 ounces plain Greek yogurt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	¼ cup fresh mint&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	¼ cup honey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INSTRUCTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place all the ingredients in a food processor or blender and blend thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31dg6vG&quot;&gt;silicone tray&lt;/a&gt;, fill the cavities about ¾ full.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place in freezer for about 2 hours or until frozen all the way through.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give to your dog for fresh breath and a great treat that also aids in digestion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/brothstickles-dog-treats.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of bone shaped frozen dog treats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-bone-brothsicles-frozen-dog-treats-by-dalmatian-diy&quot;&gt;3.	Bone Brothsicles Frozen Dog Treats by Dalmatian DIY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1 cup unseasoned bone broth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1/2 cup plain yogurt (see tips) or suitable alternative&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1/2 cup lactose-free milk or suitable alternative&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INSTRUCTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all ingredients in a bowl and mix until combined. *If you are using a thick-style yogurt, you may find it helpful to start with the yogurt and incremental add the liquids for easier mixing.*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoon into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31dg6vG&quot;&gt;silicon mold&lt;/a&gt; or suitable substitute and freeze&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait 3-4 hours or until fully frozen before removing from the molds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/frozen-apple-dog-treats.png&quot; alt=&quot;Imaage of fruit and dog ice molds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-frozen-apple-and-blueberry-treats-by-molly-says&quot;&gt;4.	Frozen Apple and Blueberry Treats by Molly Says&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1/4 Cup homemade unsalted chicken broth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1/4 Cup water&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1/4 Cup blueberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1/2 Gala apple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INSTRUCTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small bowl or glass measuring cup, mix together your unsalted chicken stock and water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash your fruits and slice your apple into small pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a couple apple pieces and a couple blueberries to your silicone dog bone molds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill your &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31dg6vG&quot;&gt;silicone dog bone molds&lt;/a&gt; up with your chicken broth/water mix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freeze for about 3 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/coconut-oil-dog-treats.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of home made coconut oil dog treats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-coconut-oil-brain-booster-treats-by-proud-dog-mom&quot;&gt;5.	Coconut Oil Brain Booster Treats By Proud Dog Mom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INGREDIENTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Coconut oil&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Almond butter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Blueberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INSTRUCTIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt a few teaspoons of coconut oil, either in a double boiler or the microwave for quick convenience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coat the bottom of each mold in a silicone tray with coconut oil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a small amount of almond butter to each mold.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a blueberry to each mold.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill the remainder of each mold with coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freeze for 15-20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>James Harrison</name></author><category term="List" /><category term="[" /><category term="&quot;French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Care&quot;," /><category term="Health&quot;," /><category term="Life" /><category term="Expectancy&quot;," /><category term="Lifespan&quot;" /><category term="]" /><category term="Frozen" /><category term="Dog" /><category term="Treats," /><category term="Frozen" /><category term="DIY" /><category term="treats," /><category term="French" /><category term="Bulldog," /><category term="French" /><category term="Bulldog" /><category term="Treats" /><summary type="html">Summer is here and our French bulldogs are as heat intolerant as ever. We explored Pinterest in search of easy DIY doggie treats that will keep our furry friends cool and entertained during the hot months.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/frozen-diy-dog-treats.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/frozen-diy-dog-treats.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">French Bulldog Health Risks – Welfare Problems Behind the Cute Face</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/french-bulldog-health-risks-welfare-problems-behind-the-cute-face/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Bulldog Health Risks – Welfare Problems Behind the Cute Face" /><published>2020-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post13</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/french-bulldog-health-risks-welfare-problems-behind-the-cute-face/">&lt;p&gt;The French Bulldog has its name on the list of the most popular dog breeds across the US. But the interest of owning one Frenchies doesn’t come solely with the high initial cost whatsoever; the &lt;strong&gt;French bulldog health risks&lt;/strong&gt; are going to add up the after-expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to researchers at The Royal Veterinary College (RVC), UK, Frenchies with their brachycephalic face, are vulnerable to spinal abnormalities, ear infections, diarrhea, and conjunctivitis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the dogs are known to be the “healthiest” of all the “bully” breeds, treatments for any suffering can be costly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why it always makes sense to get your Frenchies from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ethicalfrenchie.com&quot; title=&quot;Reputable French Bulldog Breeder&quot;&gt;a reputable breeder&lt;/a&gt; and invest in pet insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;common-french-bulldog-health-risks&quot;&gt;Common French bulldog health risks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the dramatic rise in popularity of the Frenchies is unprecedented. Dr. O’Neill from RVC worried that it was this high-demand was damaging to the French pups’ well-being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some breeders are only interested in making profit and don’t follow the necessary steps to assure the mating will produce healthy puppies. Extensive genetic testing needs to be done on the Dam and Sire to confirm they are 100% healthy before taking the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;allergies&quot;&gt;Allergies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the immune system encounters an alien substance that the body is not built to endure, it becomes a state of over-reactivity called allergies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://barkingroyalty.com/french-bulldog-allergies/&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldog Allergies&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Allergies &lt;/a&gt;can be a result of poor breeding, over-vaccination and improper care/diet. That said, your Frenchies may not be able to consume a certain type of food or intake drug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signs of allergies can take account in itchy and red skin, vomiting, diarrhea, inflamed throat, infected ears, paw chewing, and constant licking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The causes could be anything like fleas, allergens in food, pollens, dander, or even your perfume. So, there is no better solution than visiting your vet when you are unsure of what is going on that makes your Frenchies suffering. Or, at least call and consult the doctor if the case is not severe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allergies are easy to control by feeding your French Bulldog a biologically appropriate diet - which is the raw diet. Feeding kibble, especially long term can result in digestion and skin issues and an overall shorter life span - but that applies to all the breeds, not just the bulldog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/french-bulldog-care-13-best-dog-food-brands/&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldog Foods&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to learn what food with recommend for French Bulldogs with allergies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What other products do we recommend for a Frenchie struggling with allergies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2PpeUQv&quot;&gt;Colostrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Xvs1Eb&quot;&gt;Omega 3 Plankton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/39YknY3&quot;&gt;Super Mushroom Immunity Powder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;brachycephalic-respiratory-syndrome&quot;&gt;Brachycephalic Respiratory Syndrome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vcahospitals.com/know-your-pet/brachycephalic-airway-syndrome-in-dogs&quot; title=&quot;Brachycephalic respiratory syndrom&quot;&gt;Brachycephalic respiratory syndrom&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most common French bulldog health risks, refers to “a short head” or “flat face.” This means the dogs have to breathe through a short muzzle and compensate by respiring through the mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/French-bulldog-flat-face.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An image of a pied French Bulldog with a flat snout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When it comes to exercise, rather than going for one long off-lead walk every day, it is safer to take three shorter off-lead walks as brachycephalic breeds tire easily and find it difficult to breathe due to their short muzzles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important that an owner understands the needs of their pet, monitors their breathing while exercising, and takes extra precautions to ensure they don’t overdo it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the major reason for Frenchies not to be resilient to many physical efforts. Although the dogs don’t seem uncomfortable with their endowed beauty, owners should not exhaust them with extreme exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conjunctivitis-pinkeye&quot;&gt;Conjunctivitis (Pinkeye)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see your Frenchie’s eyes are getting abnormally red, it’s the sign of the inflammation of the tissues characterized in swollen and red eyelids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The causes can be allergies or dry eyes. You can rub the eyes of the dog to comfort the irritation. If you visit the vet, you may have anti-inflammation medications to relieve part of the pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s dangerous is  the consequence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For bacterial infection, antibiotic medications may be prescribed. If the cause is  allergies, it is possible to apply the elimination diet which will rule out the possible causes/foods and cut back whatever is the culprit of the sickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cherry-eye&quot;&gt;Cherry eye&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cherry eye is a disorder of the nictitating membrane (NM), also called the third eyelid, present in the eyes of dogs and cats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/French-bulldog-cherry-eye-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a french bulldog with a cherry eye condition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times the condition doesn’t present a serious health issue and can be fixed with a gentle massage. In extreme cases vet will recommend surgery to remove the tear gland. However, the postoperative result can develop dry eyes for the rest of the days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t leave this sickness untreated or it can seriously impair your Frenchie’s vision and grow into a horrible discomfort in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heat-stress&quot;&gt;Heat stress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frenchies’ smushed faces, again, bring them one more common health issue prevailing in body temperature regulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dogs usually struggle to cool themselves when the degree is up. This difficulty associated with the short face in which Frenchies can’t cool off efficiently, eventually leading to heat stroke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid playing outside during the hot summer weather. I recommend skipping the dog park during the day and scheduling it either early morning or after 7 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/French-bulldog-excercise-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a French Bulldog playing with the basketball&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know if your French pup is suffering the heat stress, notice if he is panting excessively, in convulsions or even vomiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the presence of those uncomfortable symptoms, immediately move your dog to a cooler area or at least provide some shades. Gently massage the dog’s legs and cool him down with a old pad. It is possible to place him in a bathtub if there is any - lukewarm water not cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hip-dysplasia-and-other-orthopedic-conditions&quot;&gt;Hip dysplasia and other orthopedic conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The skeletal disorder results in the disposition of socket joints of the hip. It is the first form of hip arthritis and many chronic joint pains in the long run. It’s not hard to observe the irregularity like “bunny hopping,” hip sensitivity, inability to climb stairs, unwillingness to join activities, or difficulty in standing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hip dysplasia occurs in rather bulky Frenchies than dogs with well-proportioned bodies. The causes for the disorder can be environmental, genetic or a combination of both. The disorder can also be potentially caused by an early spay, causing improper bone growth, which later one develops into hip dysplasia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treatments for such ailment can be physical therapy and diet control. A healthy diet will surely minimize the chance of meeting this illness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, a hip dysplasia surgery for French bulldog can cost from $1,600 to $5,000. The operation procedures depend on the pooch’s age, namely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Juvenile Pubic Symphysiodesis (JPS): for pups if 10 and 18 weeks old&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Double or Triple Pelvic Osteotomy (DPO/TPO): dogs of less than 8-10 months of age&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Total Hip Replacement (THR): Frenchies of at least a year old&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Femoral Head Ostectomy (FHO): for any age&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frenchiewiki.com/blog/health-problems/&quot; title=&quot;https\://www.frenchiewiki.com/blog/health-problems/&quot;&gt;https://www.frenchiewiki.com/blog/health-problems/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other common skeletal conditions in bulldogs are also &lt;a href=&quot;https://vet4bulldog.com/zen-bulldog-maintenance/orthopedics-neurology-in-bulldogs/medial-patella-luxation-in-bulldogs-and-french-bulldogs/&quot;&gt;patellar luxation&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://vet4bulldog.com/zen-bulldog-maintenance/orthopedics-neurology-in-bulldogs/elbow-dysplasia-in-bulldogs-and-french-bulldogs/&quot;&gt;elbow dysplasia.  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spinal-abnormalities-leading-into-neurological-issues&quot;&gt;Spinal Abnormalities Leading Into Neurological Issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hemivertebrae&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the potential spinal abnormalities in Bulldogs is Hemivertebrae, which  is a congenital (“at birth”, “born with”) malformation of the vertebrae seen most often in  short faced, screw tailed breeds like French, English, American Bulldogs and Pugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The abnormality might be only detectable radiographically. Most are incidental findings on a radiograph and are not associated with clinical signs. But if clinical signs arise, it’s usually due to spinal nerve compression and the dog will need further evaluation by a neurologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IVDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intervertebral disc disease (IVDD) is a condition where the cushioning discs between the vertebrae of the spinal column either bulge or burst (herniate) into the spinal cord space. These discs then press on the nerves running through the spinal cord causing pain, nerve damage, and even paralysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IVDD is a disease that effects the spinal cord over time, but it might not be apparent until there is a trigger. Unfortunately, a dog who appears to be completely healthy one day may take a fall or jump in such a way that a disc becomes ruptured. IVDD is a degenerative (gradual) process, but a jump or fall can damage a disc that has already been weakened by IVDD and bring on an acute phase of the disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Symptoms can range from mild to severe and can include:
**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Unwillingness to jump&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Pain and weakness in rear legs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Knuckling under&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Paralysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Crying out in pain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Muscle spasms over back or neck&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Hunched back or neck with tense muscles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Reduced appetite and activity level&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Loss of bladder and/or bowel control&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deafness---irresponsible-breeding-practices&quot;&gt;Deafness - Irresponsible Breeding Practices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inability to hear can come from genetic defects. It also happens in senior dogs. People reckon extreme pied French Bulldogs, the dogs with genes associated with the lack of pigment cells, are the kind that is prone to this hearing loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/White-French-Bulldog-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a white french bulldog puppy playing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be funny to think how the color affects the listening ability, but there are indeed little hairs called cilia that don’t grow without the presence of pigment cells causing deafness in Frenchies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The high risk is present in dogs who are all white, or Pied French Bulldogs with little to no markings in the ear area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A responsible breeder will make sure the Dam and Sire are a genetic match before mating them to avoid this from happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take your dog to a clinic and request a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bluepearlvet.com/medical-articles/baer-test-for-hearing-loss/&quot; title=&quot;BEAR test for dogs&quot;&gt;BAER test&lt;/a&gt; to diagnose the hearing ability for French pups as young as 6 weeks old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;In Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking care of a brachycephalic pet is not a picnic work. It requires extreme care and love; on the other side is finance and patience to look after the &lt;strong&gt;French Bulldog health risks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, please think responsibly before you want to adopt a French bulldog. Consider if you have enough time and money to give the dog a healthy yet fulfilled life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, never think you can get a Frenchies under $500 or else it’s a scam. Remember that poor breeding is the primary trigger of many negatives that come after. So, don’t buy or encourage any cheap breeder even with exclusive deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/why-french-bulldogs-are-expensive-before-adoption/&quot; title=&quot;Why French Bulldogs are expensive&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to learn why French Bulldogs are expensive in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Health Issues" /><category term="French Bulldog Allergies" /><category term="French Bulldog Cherry Eye" /><category term="French Bulldog Health Risks" /><category term="French Bulldog Health" /><category term="French Bulldog Health Issues" /><category term="French Bulldog Allergies" /><category term="French Bulldog Cherry Eye" /><category term="French Bulldog Health Risks" /><category term="French Bulldog Health" /><summary type="html">The French Bulldog has its name on the list of the most popular dog breeds across the US. But the interest of owning one Frenchies doesn’t come solely with the high initial cost whatsoever; the French bulldog health risks are going to add up the after-expenses.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/bulldog-health-risks.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/bulldog-health-risks.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Increase French Bulldog Lifespan With These Simple Steps</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/increase-french-bulldog-lifespan" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Increase French Bulldog Lifespan With These Simple Steps" /><published>2020-03-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post14</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/increase-french-bulldog-lifespan">&lt;h2 id=&quot;french-bulldog-lifespan-is-generally-between-10-14-years-breed-and-genetics-do-play-a-role-but-there-are-still-many-factors-within-your-control-make-these-small-changes-today-to-increase-your-french-bulldogs-longevity&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Lifespan is generally between 10-14 years. Breed and genetics do play a role, but there are still many factors within your control. Make these small changes today to increase your French Bulldog’s longevity.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-oral-care&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Oral Care&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t emphasize this enough. Keep your Frenchies teeth clean. If you are feeding your dog the appropriate diet, which is the raw diet that consists of raw meaty bones, then teeth hygiene will not be a problem. BUT if you are feeding some other type of food, like kibble than daily or at least weekly brushing is a MUST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why is this important you ask?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well,  dogs over the age of 3 have a 85% chance of getting some form of gum disease. Bacteria builds up over the years and can cause  gingivitis and other forms of disease in the oral cavity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harmful bacteria and toxins will enter the body via the bleeding gums and affect the vital organs, especially in older Frenchies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oral care alone can add up to 2 year to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/increase-french-bulldog-lifespan&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;French Bulldog’s lifespan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2DyWvhC&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you aren’t a fan of brushing, you can always use this water additive to support healthy gums.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-raw-food-diet&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Raw Food Diet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Raw-turkey-meat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of raw chicken and beef meat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid commercial processed dog foods. Most  commercial dog foods ( kibble) are full of inferior sources of protein, also known as fillers. Inspect the ingredient list - if it contains a substantial amount of corn, wheat, soy or white rice, it’s time to switch to a more canine appropriate food brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, let’s do a little test. Take your dog’s food and soak it in a bowl of water. Let it sit for 15-20 minutes. If it blows up and becomes spongy - your basically feeding your dog a diet that consists of cereal and not meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would recommend feeding you French Bulldog a Raw Food diet with a high quality proteinand bones as it’s first ingredient. If you simply cannot stomach preparing raw food then commercial raw food is the way to go. Freshly cooked is OK, but keep in mind as soon as the protein is damaged by cooking, your dog doesn’t benefit from it as much. And don’t forget there is also the freeze dried raw option if handling raw meat goes against everything you stand for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on a budget and can only afford to feed kibble, then add fresh ingredients to your dog’s kibble. Even a small amount will make a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few things you can add to your dogs kibble are:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3kdQ1FK&quot;&gt;Bone broth (you can make it at home as well)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2EJ0LLQ&quot;&gt;2. Probiotics and Enzymes &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31nvoOA&quot;&gt;3. Freeze dried food toppers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Xubvo2&quot;&gt;4. Omega 3 Plankton &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3gGRm5T&quot;&gt;5. Cold pressed hemp seed oil &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raw leafy greens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/igcta4.png&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/french-bulldog-care-13-best-dog-food-brands/&quot; title=&quot;Best French Bulldog Foods&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click here to check some of the dog foods we highly recommend.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-avoid-anything-containing-sunflower-oil-and-corn&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Avoid Anything Containing Sunflower Oil and Corn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies have shown that Sunflower oil increases cancer in dogs by 69%. Why do so many dog food brands still use it as an ingredient? Hmm..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We mentioned corn in the first paragraph of this blog. It’s a well know allergen in dogs and just overall not a good ingredient, since is difficult to digest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra work involved in processing it can cause premature aging in so many dogs. Let’s explain why. After ingesting corn (which is an inferior form of protein) the liver needs to work extra hard to get the usable protein out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breakdown of corn also produces a lot of nitrates, which put extra strain on the kidneys - since they have to filter out the toxins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starches aren’t something dogs should be regularly eating, but unfortunately almost every kibble on the market contains just that. Which is why it’s best to avoid kibble all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-joint-support&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Joint Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joints that are wasting away are very painful. Just like in humans the stress from chronic pain can also weaken the immune system, making your Frenchie susceptible to even more countless health problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is generally agreed that French Bulldogs are more prone to hip dysplasia, but that does not mean it’s a sentence to a shorter life span.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to keep the joints healthy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your doggo lean. Extra weight will put stress on the joints. Keep your Frenchie the leanest possible without it being visibly undernourished. Good muscle tone, ribs that are easily felt but not visible, no love handles…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feed raw meaty bones like chicken wings, turkey necks, chicken necks, chicken backs. All these bones are very healthy for your dog - in raw form and your pup will be able to crush and ingest the whole thing. RAW not cooked. Never give your dog a cooked bone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invest in a good joint supplement. Chances are your dog isn’t getting the significant amount needed from the commercial food brand he’s eating. If you were raw feeding your canine friend from the start, the chances of joint disease creeping up are lower. But if you haven’t then I recommend using something like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3i622uW&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agility Formula by Life’s Abundance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-use-organic-household-products&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Use Organic Household Products&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the household product that we use daily for either cleaning the floors, kitchen surfaces, windows, all the air-fresheners, laundry detergents, etc, cause health issues for humans and have been a proven carcinogen, think about how that affects the smallest members of our family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldogs love lounging around on the floors and are notorious for licking and chewing on stuff, which puts them directly at risk of ingesting the harmful ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be mindful next time you’re buying cleaning supplies. Keep things natural and organic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We own multiple French Bulldogs, so there is always lots of cleaning to do, BUT the cleaning is always done with gentle pet friendly household products like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3kbOpvY&quot;&gt;ECOS Earth Friendly ALL PURPOSE cleaner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2XJy88f&quot;&gt;Aunt Fannies Vinegar Wash Floor Cleaner Eucalyptus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/33qFoJD&quot;&gt;Seventh Generation Concentrated Laundry Detergent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-regular-vet-check-ups&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Regular Vet Check Ups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../uploads/French-bulldog-walking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of an adorable pied french bulldog walking on a leash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait until it’s too late. Find a trustworthy and honest vet that has your Frenchies best interest at heart. Do a yearly blood work panel to detect any abnormalities, especially in older dogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep your pooch up to date on shots, but don’t over-vaccinate. Some vaccines like Lyme and Lepto, have been proven to cause allergic reactions and long-term issues with the bulldog breed, and should in my opinion be avoided, &lt;strong&gt;unless strictly advised by your vet due to your highly-risky geographical location.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-doggie-stairs&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Doggie Stairs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldogs are prone to IVDD - Intervertebral disk disease (IVDD), often referred to as a slipped or herniated disk, refers to a syndrome of pain and neurological problems that accompany degeneration of one or more intervertebral disks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thepetwiki.com/wiki/intervertibral_disc_disease/&quot; title=&quot;IVDD in dogs&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click here to learn more about IVDD in dogs and the most common symptoms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can prevent this from happening by simply training your Frenchie to use the doggie stairs instead of jumping on and off of high surfaces (beds, couches, stairs,…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many young French Bulldogs end up paralyzed, or worse, euthanized due to the irreversible effects of IVDD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a Frenchie owner - doggie stairs should be a must in your household.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2XqunV2&quot;&gt;Zinus Step Comfort Pet Stairs/Pet Ramp/Pet Ladder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2XsllGW&quot;&gt;Nova Microdermabrasion Pet Dog Stairs Steps for high Bed for Small Dogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we provided some insight and useful information about how to increase &lt;strong&gt;French Bulldog lifespan&lt;/strong&gt;. Our canine companions deserve nothing but the best when it comes to their care and well being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course they won’t be around forever, but with these easy tips, they can reach a higher life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="French Bulldog Care" /><category term="French Bulldog Health" /><category term="French Bulldog Life Expectancy" /><category term="French Bulldog Lifespan" /><category term="French Bulldog Care" /><category term="French Bulldog Health" /><category term="French Bulldog Life Expectancy" /><category term="French Bulldog Lifespan" /><summary type="html">French Bulldog Lifespan is generally between 10-14 years. Breed and genetics do play a role, but there are still many factors within your control. Make these small changes today to increase your French Bulldog’s longevity.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/increase-french-bulldog-lifespan.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/increase-french-bulldog-lifespan.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">French Bulldog Feeding: The Raw Diet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-feeding-the-raw-diet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Bulldog Feeding: The Raw Diet" /><published>2020-02-12T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-12T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-feeding-the-raw-diet/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;french-bulldog-feeding-the-raw-diet&quot;&gt;French Bulldog Feeding: The Raw Diet&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;should-i-feed-my-french-bulldog-the-raw-food-diet&quot;&gt;Should I Feed My French Bulldog the Raw Food Diet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All dog owners want the absolute best for their furry companions to make sure they stick around for as long as possible and live a healthy, happy and active life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A balanced, biologically appropriate diet is the first step towards achieving that goal. Historically, dry dog kibble and canned dog food were the only choices on the market. But over the years, people became more familiar with different options like the fresh food or raw food diets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog we will dive deeper into the raw food diet, it’s benefits, risks and frequent misconceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-raw-dog-food-diet&quot;&gt;What is the raw dog food diet?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raw_feeding&quot;&gt;B.A.R.F diet&lt;/a&gt; stands for two common phrases: ‘Biologically Appropriate Raw Food’ and ‘Bones and Raw Food’. Founded by veterinarian and nutritionist Dr. Ian Billinghurst, the principle is to feed dogs the diet they evolved to eat—a raw diet composed of meats and greens that are fresh, uncooked and wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The genetic makeup of domesticated dogs supports this. From Boston Terriers to St. Bernards, dogs are essentially the same as their ancestors, gray wolves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As direct descendants of wolves, dogs are simply not genetically optimized to consume the 50% carbohydrate content of today’s commercial kibbles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recommended guidelines for a BARF diet consists of 70% muscle meat, 10% raw edible bone, 7% vegetables, 5% liver, 5% other secreting organ, 2% seeds or nuts, and 1% fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-benefits-of-raw-feeding&quot;&gt;What are the benefits of raw feeding?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Firmer stools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Improved digestion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Healthier skin and coat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Reduced allergy symptoms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Leaner, more muscular build;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 60% of dogs are overweight or obese based on body condition scoring, which leads to a number of related conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been many reports of improved health when chronically ill pets were switched from a commercial product to a raw dog food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-downsides-of-raw-feeding&quot;&gt;The downsides of raw feeding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally think the benefits outweigh the downsides, but it comes down to every individual and their budget as well as their household situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	First downside would be the inconvenience of feeding raw vs. feeding kibble. Raw food has a shorter shelf life and needs to be refrigerated/freezed at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Second is the possibility of contamination – for humans. The dogs have a short and acidic digestive system, so they aren’t susceptible to Salmonella or E-coli infections. Always wash your food after handling raw food. Wash the dog bowl with soap and warm water right after feeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/raw_feeding_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of French Bulldog Raw Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;frequent-misconceptions-about-raw-feeding&quot;&gt;Frequent Misconceptions About Raw Feeding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Raw meat is contaminated/infested with parasites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick meat that is labeled as “human grade”, that meat is inspected and clear of parasites. I would however steer away from wild meat (bear, beaver, wild pig, etc.). Bacteria is found everywhere, even on kibble, but dogs have a short digestive track and usually aren’t affected by Salmonella or E-coli, like I mentioned before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**2. My veterinary advised against raw feeding and suggested the science diet instead. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to understand that “veterinarian” doesn’t equal “nutritionist”. Most vets have very little nutritional training, and what they get in school is funded by the pet food companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vets that don’t understand the dietary needs of dogs (and cats) will recommend kibble or canned food, so that each meal is complete and balanced. They will tell you that your dog will get salmonella or e-coli from raw meat, etc..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dogs eat poop, road kill and lick their behinds every day. . Their system is different from ours. If we ate the stuff they did, we would for sure get very sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_ Dogs have a short digestive system made to handle raw meat and bones(raw bones, NEVER COOKED BONES), the bacteria that is present isn’t a problem for a healthy dog. _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Is kibble bad for my dog? My dog has been eating it for years and had no issues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do I start with this one.. First dogs don’t have a nutritional need for ingredients like wheat, corn, etc and the grains and fillers in the commercial dog food are often the root of allergies and digestion issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most commercial dog foods also have artificial color, sugar, artificial flavoring, too much salt, etc.. The goal of adding all these things is to make them flavorful and appealing to your dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kibble is cooked on extremely high temperatures which destroys most of the nutrients that are beneficial to your dog&lt;/strong&gt; (enzymes, vitamins, beneficial bacteria, fatty acids). The processing kibble goes through makes all the dogs internal organs work harder to extract the nutrients that have survived the extruding process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kibble industry of course improved a lot. There are many “grain free” and “organic” kibble options, but at the end of the day you are still feeding your dog a highly processed, nutritionally low meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Dogs just like human can SURVIVE on a low quality diet(read fast food), but they can’t THRIVE on it. Feed your dog a species appropriate nutrition and watch him live a long, healthy, issue free life.**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-raw-feed-your-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;How To Raw Feed Your French Bulldog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-frozen-and-dehydrated-raw-food-brands&quot;&gt;1. Frozen and Dehydrated Raw Food Brands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pet Smart and Pet Co carry most of these option. The difference between frozen and freeze dried/dehydrated is the storing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to keep the dehydrated raw food in the fridge and it’s completely safe so carry it around. It’s best to re-hydrate is before serving by using bone broth, warm water, goat milk..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Finstinct-by-natures-variety-frozen%2Fdp%2F170898&quot;&gt;Instinct Frozen Raw Pet Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fprimal-chicken-formula-nuggets-grain%2Fdp%2F43376&quot;&gt;Primal Dehydrated Raw Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fstella-chewys-duck-duck-goose-dinner%2Fdp%2F121086&quot;&gt;Stella&amp;amp;Chewy’s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fnulo-freestyle-grain-free-duck-recipe%2Fdp%2F162466&quot;&gt;Nulo Freeze Dried Raw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fhonest-kitchen-grain-free-chicken%2Fdp%2F34268&quot;&gt;The Honest Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fspot-farms-grain-free-duck-dehydrated%2Fdp%2F177172&quot;&gt;Spot Farms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fvisionary-pet-foods-raw-frozen-keto%2Fdp%2F177390&quot;&gt;Visionary Keto Pet Foods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/raw_feeding_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Frozen Foods&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-raw-food-subscriptions&quot;&gt;2. Raw Food Subscriptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t to fond of preparing your own meal, or confused about creating a balanced meal you can always rely on experts to do it for you. Below are some raw food subscription services that will bring the food to your door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wefeedraw.com/&quot;&gt;We Feed Raw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://primalpooch.com/&quot;&gt;Primal Pooch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rawwild.com/&quot;&gt;Raw Wild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mypetcarnivore.com/&quot;&gt;My Pet Carnivore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rawpawspetfood.com/&quot;&gt;Raw Paws Pet Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-preparing-your-own-raw-food&quot;&gt;3. Preparing Your Own Raw Food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true, raw food subscriptions and food brands tend to be more expensive, but you can choose the cheaper route and prepare the meals yourself. You definitely need to be careful and do a lot of research to make sure you are balancing the nutrients correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What should the basic raw meal structure look like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	1 ½ cups of raw meat, partially on the bone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	½ veggies and fruit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Multivitamin/mineral product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Omega 3 in a form of fish oil or general omega 3 supplement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**How much should you feed? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An adult dog needs to eat just over 2% of his bodyweight in food each day (whether it’s raw dog food, or homemade food that you’re cooking for him).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for a 10lb dog that’s just under 1/4lb of food; for a 50lb dog just over 1lb, and for a 100lb dog about 2.5lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use this guide to figure out how much your dog needs, but of course bear in mind that all dogs are different and that these figures are guidelines only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Ratio can be 75% - 95% meat/bones/organs and 5% -25% vegetables&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	The bones in any raw dog food recipe should have an equal amount of meat and bone (ie a 1:1 ratio). Big bones with just a little bit of meat aren’t nearly as good as smaller bones with more meat on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Overall bone to meat ratio can be approx 1:3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/raw_feeding_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Types of Raw Meat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-kind-of-meat-you-should-use&quot;&gt;What kind of meat you should use:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Chicken - chicken necks, thighs, wings and even feet are great choices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Turkey - as above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Duck - as above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Lamb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Beef&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Rabbit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Venison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Wild game birds such as Pheasant or Partridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Organ Meat such as liver, kidneys and so on are excellent, but rich, so use sparingly at first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Whole fish of just about any kind are fine, but raw salmon often isn’t recommended&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;safe-to-use-vegetables&quot;&gt;Safe to use vegetables:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Brussel Sprouts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Carrots&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Cauliflower&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Okra&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Green Beans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Peas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Pumpkin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Squash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Romaine Lettuce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Parsley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Celery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Sweet Potatoes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;safe-to-use-fruits&quot;&gt;Safe to use fruits:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Apples (pitts are poisonous, make sure to remove them)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Bananas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Pears&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Strawberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Blueberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;extra-ingredients-you-could-add&quot;&gt;Extra ingredients you could add:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other ingredients that can be used to add variety and extra nutritional value to raw dog food recipes.
 They do not need to be added daily, and once or twice a week for most is generally enough…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Kefir as a probiotic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Raw Eggs - including the shells which need to be ground to a fine powder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Almonds (NOT Macadamia Nuts)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Sunflower seeds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Wheatgrass&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Kelp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this blog convinced you or at least opened your mind to  benefits of raw feeding. Like I mentioned before, I do understand that kibble is way more convenient, but the BARF diet is a diet closest to your dogs origin and  proven to help maintain longevity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>renee</name></author><category term="french bulldog" /><category term="frenchie puppy" /><category term="French Bulldog Feeding" /><category term="picks" /><summary type="html">French Bulldog Feeding: The Raw Diet</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/raw_feeding.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/raw_feeding.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">French Bulldogs and New York Lottery | Here to Make Your Day with Frenchies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-television-commercial-new-york-lottery-animal-actors-inc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="French Bulldogs and New York Lottery | Here to Make Your Day with Frenchies" /><published>2020-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post27</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/french-bulldog-television-commercial-new-york-lottery-animal-actors-inc/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;french-bulldogs-on-tv&quot;&gt;French Bulldogs on TV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look Ma! We’re on TV!  2019 Was a great year for Ethical Frenchie, one of many lessons and many new friends. So it was only fitting that we would receive a random call from Animal Actors Inc telling us that “we’re up next”. The read carpet was roleld out and our babies were ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;uk-section uk-section-large&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;uk-container uk-container-xsmall uk-position-relative uk-text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section-title-center uk-margin-large-bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-title uk-margin-remove uk-text-center&quot;&gt;Behind The Scenes!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;div&gt;
    
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;uk-article-content&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:6.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/390228658?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we didn’t exactly have the diversity of puppies needed we jumped on the phone and called our customers whom had recently adopted puppies from us to ask “Would you like to see your puppy on TV!?”  Every single family responded relucantly :-( which shows exactly how passionate our furever homes are when we place puppies.   Alas, we found a couple extra to stand in with the puppies of ours and it was lights camera action!   Below are some of the clips of what its like on a real tv commercial shoot (And of course, They were the most popular attraction on the whole film studio lot)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t Forget to Follow Us on Instagram Below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/ethicalfrenchie&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/uploads/IGCTA2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;instagram cta 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once again thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;Animal Actors INC&quot;&gt;http://www.animalactorsinc.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¹ Animal Actors Inc, Ethical Frenchie LLC, New York Lotto&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>james</name></author><category term="french bulldog" /><category term="frenchie puppy" /><category term="French Bulldog puppy" /><category term="news" /><category term="picks" /><summary type="html">French Bulldogs on TV</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/nylotto.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/nylotto.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ethical Frenchie’s Guide To Dog Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/ethical-frenchie-guide-to-dog-health/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ethical Frenchie’s Guide To Dog Health" /><published>2020-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/post23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/ethical-frenchie-guide-to-dog-health/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/sick-french-bulldog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of a sick french bulldog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-guide-to-raising-a-healthy-french-bulldog&quot;&gt;Our Guide To Raising a Healthy French Bulldog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s well known that &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/ethical-frenchie-guide-to-dog-health/&quot; title=&quot;French Bulldogs Health&quot;&gt;French Bulldogs &lt;/a&gt; fall under one of those “sensitive” and “issue prone” breeds. And there is no denying that purebred dogs tend to be susceptible to sickness more than mutts, which is due to the smaller genetic diversity pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing to keep in mind is things aren’t always black and white. 
Just like with humans, it’s possible to avoid genetic issues and susceptibilities with your dogs as well, and food plays a big role. So let’s start with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;food&quot;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gut represents 80% of your dog’s immune system. It’s important to keep the gut flora balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do that by feeding your Frenchie companion a diet they were designed to eat. The best way to go at it is by preparing your own meals (fresh or raw), or investing in a good fresh food subscription service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Dogs are designed to eat a moist diet that consists of meat as its first ingredients, as well as some fresh vegetables. **
Kibble is problematic, due to it’s high starch content. Starch is well known to cause inflammation and definitely does not support a healthy microbiome for dogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live bacteria from fresh food on the other hand promotes just that. It’s vital to include it into your dog’s everyday meal. If you are still loyal to kibble – boost it with fresh ingredients daily.
Also, adding a quality probiotic never hurts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fhonest-kitchen-daily-boosters-instant%2Fdp%2F177081&quot;&gt;You can get one here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;turmeric-golden-paste-food-booster&quot;&gt;Turmeric Golden Paste Food Booster&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/tumeric.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Tumeric as a supplement for Frenchies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Have you every heard of the incredible healing effects of curcumin? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curcumin is the main compound of turmeric and can fight allergies, relieve pain, boost the immune system and prevent cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many turmeric dog supplements available online, but there ain’t nothing like the home-made thing, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This turmeric golden paste is super easy to make and will last your for about 2 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;INGREDIENTS:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup organic turmeric powder (Organic turmeric powder contains more curcumin)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 to 1 ½ cups filtered water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ teaspoons freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup organic cold pressed or coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;DIRECTIONS:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Mix the turmeric with the water in a pan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Start with 1 cup water and add more only if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Stir the liquid on medium/low heat and in about 7 to 10 minutes, it should form a thick paste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  If your paste looks watery, just add a bit more turmeric and heat it for another couple of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Once you’ve got a paste, add the pepper and oil, then stir it very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•  Allow the mixture to cool, then place it in a jar with a lid and store it in your fridge. Ideally, you should store the paste for no more than two weeks … after that, you’ll want to make a fresh batch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Start by adding ¼ to your Frenchie’s meal. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-allergies-arise-try-fighting-them-naturally-first&quot;&gt;If Allergies Arise Try Fighting Them Naturally First&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veterinary prescribed medication is very effective, but it should be considered the last resort. It removes the reaction to the allergen by suppressing the immune system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is once the immune system is suppressed the body becomes a target for many different illnesses, including cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your French Bulldog is suffering from uncontrollable allergies and none of the natural remedies are doing the trick, the next step would be doing a simple allergy test to determinate the trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The allergen can be anything from food, pollen, certain types of grass and even human dandruff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogsnaturallymagazine.com/why-i-dont-vaccinate-my-dogs-at-all/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Full article here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-challenge-the-immune-system-with-any-vaccines-unless-100-necessary&quot;&gt;Don’t Challenge The Immune System With Any Vaccines, Unless 100% Necessary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/vaccine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of canine vaccine as a supplement for Frenchies&quot; title=&quot;Vaccine for French Bulldogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vaccines are a wonderful thing. In fact 80% of little puppies would never make it through their first few months of life without them. Their immune system is week and undeveloped, so diseases like Parvo, Distemper, etc can be deadly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However… over vaccinating became a huge problem in the last decade. The vaccines your tiny Frenchie pup gets give him protection to up to 7 years, so why are we vaccinating our pets and giving them boosters yearly? Rabies vaccine is required by law and 100% necessary. **The other ones? Not so much. **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read an article that spoke to me, so I had to share. And I quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;” Our dogs are in the midst of an epidemic. It’s not an epidemic of viral disease, but of chronic ill health. They’re besieged with itchy, pus-laden, scabby skin; vomit and diarrhea are the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One in every hundred dogs suffers from epilepsy, and an even higher number of  dogs live with painful arthritis.  Allergies are also reaching epidemic proportions: dogs are becoming allergic to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Dr Jean W Dodds, an eminent vet and researcher, both allergic and autoimmune diseases have been rising since the introduction of modified live virus vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autoimmune diseases are where the body attacks self; they include cancer, leukemia, thyroid disease, Addisons, Grave’s disease, autoimmune hemolytic anemia, rheumatoid arthritis, diabetes, lupus, thrombocytopenia, organ failure, skin inflammations, and more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/creativeref:1011l31349&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://creative.prf.hn/source/camref:1100l86im/creativeref:1011l31349&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;brush-those-teeth&quot;&gt;Brush Those Teeth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago we posted a blog called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethicalfrenchie.com/blog/increase-french-bulldog-lifespan&quot;&gt;Increasing French Bulldog Lifespan&lt;/a&gt;”, and pointed out how important oral care actually is. You should brush your Frenchie’s teeth as often as possible, and 1x per week at a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your Frenchie isn’t fond of the teeth brushing ritual, make sure you ad least invest in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Ftropiclean-fresh-breath-drops-22oz%2Fdp%2F114717&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fresh Breath water additive like this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie, life gets hectic and even I don’t brush my dogs teeth everyday, I do however use the water additive constantly as it promotes oral health and fights bad puppy breath as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-your-frenchie-slim&quot;&gt;Keep Your Frenchie Slim&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/slim-frenchie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of quite chubby frenchies&quot; title=&quot;Rather chubby French Bulldogs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French Bulldogs are naturally wide and stocky, but wide and stocky doesn’t equal chunky. You might think it looks cute and adorable seeing a Frenchie with a few extra rolls, but it’s far from that. It’s dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People don’t realize that 70% of family pets are overweight. A healthy French Bulldog should be slim, muscular, and the rib cage should be easily visible with every inhale. 
Even though they are known as the perfect apartment dog, cuddle buddy and couch potato, they still require a certain level of exercise to maintain a healthy figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting your French Bulldog get overweight will bring a series of problems, including arthritis, hearth, breathing and eye problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Think of it as a domino effect, and I’ll give an example. 
**Let’s say your Frenchie is overweight and the excess weight is overwhelming the joints leading to arthritis. Arthritis causes major discomfort and the state of pain is known to weaken the immune system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weak immune system makes the host more susceptible to other life-threatening conditions, including cancer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feed a quality diet, without overfeeding, and remember less is more. Don’t feed table scraps – a small piece of cheese ingested by your dog equals a chocolate bar ingested by a human. If you want to provide a heathy in between the meal snack for your Frenchie – try carrots or blueberries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;supplements-you-should-consider-using&quot;&gt;Supplements You Should Consider Using&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Falaska-naturals-wild-alaskan-salmon%2Fdp%2F105390&quot;&gt;• Omega 3 Supplement or regular Fish Oil&lt;/a&gt; {:target=”_blank”}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fhonest-kitchen-daily-boosters-instant%2Fdp%2F177081&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;• Quality Probiotic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/pubref:renee/adref:ethicalfrenchie/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fhealers-turmeric-golden-paste-mix-dog%2Fdp%2F203177&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Turmeric Supplement or the DIY Turmeric Golden Paste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fzesty-paws-mobility-bites-hip-joint%2Fdp%2F226707&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Glucosamine Joint Supplement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/destination:https%3A%2F%2Fwww.chewy.com%2Fonly-natural-pet-free-range-chicken%2Fdp%2F179023&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bone Broth to rehydrate dry kibble food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://prf.hn/click/camref:1100l86im/creativeref:1100l29658&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://creative.prf.hn/source/camref:1100l86im/creativeref:1100l29658&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; width=&quot;222&quot; height=&quot;143&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on the market for a new family member, &lt;a href=&quot;/puppies&quot;&gt;check out our puppies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>renee</name></author><category term="french bulldog" /><category term="scams" /><category term="frenchie puppy" /><category term="French Bulldog Health Issues" /><category term="news" /><category term="picks" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/fawn-sick-french-bulldog.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/fawn-sick-french-bulldog.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>